<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[/dev/admin]]></title>
  <link href="http://logikal.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://logikal.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-24T12:38:34-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://logikal.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sean Kilgore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boundaries]]></title>
    <link href="http://logikal.github.com/blog/2012/04/24/boundaries/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-24T01:20:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://logikal.github.com/blog/2012/04/24/boundaries</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/log1kal/status/194699562647162881">tweeted</a> earlier, and realized that some people might like to know what I was talking about.</p>

<pre><code>Me: my current goals can be summed up by saying something like "I want to work for GitHub"  
(Option1) was a better road to that than (Option2)  

Him: You want to be apart of the change you feel needs to be in the world

Me: exactly

Him:   
and not on the level that (redacted) is  
you want to be the edge that he points to  

Me:   
yeah  
interesting thing about edges and boundaries  
thats where the cool stuff happens  
that's where pioneering happens   
and if we can keep ourselves from putting up stupid walls, the world will be a better place  
__github embodies the kind of pioneering without walls that I want to be a part of__  
</code></pre>

<p>It&#8217;s no secret that I&#8217;m a big fan of GitHub. I try to get into whatever talk/drinkup/whatever they&#8217;re doing when one of them comes down my way. <a href="http://scottchacon.com/">Scott Chacon</a> gave a talk in Ventura, and explained how GitHub started from first principles. They didn&#8217;t ask &#8220;How has this been done for the last 30 years?&#8221; or &#8220;What&#8217;s the normal way a business is run?&#8221; They asked &#8221;<strong>What&#8217;s the best way to get this done so we can work on our product?</strong>&#8221;</p>

<p>And then they went out and told everyone about it.</p>

<p>I really feel that GitHub is a company on the edge of what&#8217;s normal. And instead of keeping it to themselves (which would quite frankly give them a competitive edge), they&#8217;ll tell anyone who wants to listen how they started from 3 guys who wanted a better way to host open-source products, and turned out to be a major driver of change, even <a href="http://radar.oreilly.com/2012/01/with-govuk-british-government.html">change</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/github/status/190934305999028225">outside</a> of their immediate sphere of influence.</p>

<p>More info: http://www.wired.com/wiredenterprise/2012/02/github/all/1</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vagrant: streamlined dev environments]]></title>
    <link href="http://logikal.github.com/blog/2012/04/11/vagrant-streamlined-dev-environments/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T01:33:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://logikal.github.com/blog/2012/04/11/vagrant-streamlined-dev-environments</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a need to write some code recently, and ran into the &#8220;Rails is a pain to set up&#8221; issue that people have been talking about recently. It&#8217;s gotten bad enough that <a href="http://yehudakatz.com/">Yehuda Katz</a>, a member of the Ruby on Rails core team, has set up a Kickstarter project, <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1397300529/railsapp">&#8220;Rails.app&#8221;</a>, to address the issue.</p>

<p>Since I&#8217;m more familiar with running services on something more like an Amazon EC2 instance, I looked around for something I could put some time and secret sauce into that would give me ease of use and reusability.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s when I found <a href="http://vagrantup.com">Vagrant</a>.</p>

<p>Vagrant is a way to spin up VMs with standardized environments very quickly. It depends on the wonderful <a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/">Oracle Virtualbox</a>, and can even integrate <a href="http://www.opscode.com/chef/">Chef</a> or <a href="http://puppetlabs.com/">Puppet</a>.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll write a bit more about my experiance with Vagrant soon. You should start looking at it now, though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
